Changing two.
Sheesh, more junk?
Stop dawdling around!
Okay, I'll also change two.
There it is!
Say, Brother,
want to double the bet?
Suit yourself.
Sorry, but I have a full house.
Sorry, but I have
a royal straight flush.
No way! I lose again?!
All right, this time for sure...
I'm out. This is boring.
What's wrong, Brother?
You've done nothing but win for a while.
Are you bored from only winning?
It has nothing to do with the cards.
The problem is...
Colonel Mustang.
You don't want to see him.
Of course not!
It turns out that the
Philosopher's Stone was a fake,
and we haven't produced
any other results, after all.
That may be true...
Just watch as I give my report.
This is Colonel Mustang
we're talking about.
The kinds of sarcastic
things he'll say to me...
Just imagining it
puts me in a nasty mood.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Are you sure this is okay, Brother?
Getting off the train along the way?
We're okay.
You never know where information leading to the Philosopher's Stone might be lying around, after all.
Besides, Aquroya is a famous tourist spot.
It wouldn't hurt to
have a look at it, right?
It sort of feels like we're playing hooky from school, huh?
Who's playing hooky?!
What's this?!
Brother, by any chance...
Wait up, Brother!
You cheater! You cheated! Brother, you're a cheater!
After her! Don't let her escape!
Today's the day we catch Psiren!
All right, that's far enough.
You've got nowhere to run, Psiren!
Hey, hold it!
It's a pretty city, isn't it, Brother?
Isn't it?
The City of Water, Aquroya,
is a famous sightseeing area.
This is far better than going to that dusty East City,
and having to look into that
cynical face of the Colonel's.
How the hell could you do that?!
It is the City of Water, after all.
What do you want, Pops? Yow!
You're coming to
the station with me.
There's something
I want to ask you about.
So, you're a State Alchemist, then?
And the famous Fullmetal one, at that.
How many times are you going to make me say it?
That should be more
proof than anything!
If it's the real thing, that is.
How a pipsqueak like you could be—
Who are you calling a pee-wee so small
that you instinctively want to step on him?!
Brother, nobody said anything like that.
Now, now, don't get so worked up.
Right now, we have an unidentified phantom thief in the city
who goes by the name of "Psiren" plaguing us.
Psiren?
We only have one thing
that you could call a lead.
And that's the fact that Psiren uses alchemy.
You're an alchemist too, right?
That's why I thought I would hear what you have to say.
Damn that guy!
He kept repeating the same questions for three whole hours.
What is he using for brains?
But, Brother, doesn't it bother you? I mean, an alchemist thief...
Well, I...
Brother?
What's wrong?
M-My stomach...
It's some mild food poisoning.
You didn't just eat
too much, then.
Leave me alone.
Better give you a shot. Clara-kun!
Yes?
A shot?
Yes, a shot.
No way! I hate shots!
Brother! Don't make a scene!
I'm okay! I'm already better!
You're not a child!
Here, take off your coat!
Stop, Al! Are you trying to
sell your brother out here?!
You're going to make me mad, Brother!
Aah! I hate shots!
There!
Your shot is all done.
That didn't hurt, did it?
I-I didn't even notice...
That was incredibly fast work...
Say, listen...
Wh-What?
You need to grow up soon.
M-Mind your own business.
She sure was a pretty nurse, huh?
I unexpectedly found myself fascinated by her.
What kind of taste
have you got, anyhow?
What's so good about
a woman like her?
This won't do, ma'am.
You've left so much here.
I'm sorry,
but I just can't get them down.
I can't help you there. Well...
How about I peel another piece of fruit for you?
Are you all right with that?
This is no problem.
That looks dangerous. I'll do it.
Let me have it, Brother.
I'm okay. Back off!
There...
You two eat.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing. Still...
Clara-san isn't just pretty.
She's kind, too.
She kind of resembles Mom a little bit.
Don't be ridiculous!
They're completely different!
I-I'm sorry.
That's okay, ma'am.
Don't worry about it.
Here.
You two are alchemists?
Elric! Mr. Elric!
Now what, Pops?!
I'm not a thief!
I know, I know.
The truth is, I have a request.
We salute the State Alchemist, Edward Elric-sensei!
Yikes.
What are you up to, Pops?
No, no, no, I'm sorry about earlier.
As you said, Sensei,
I inquired of Commander Mustang of the Eastern Command Center.
When I did, it turned out that you really are a State Alchemist, Sensei!
My, my, I truly underestimated you!
Isn't that what I said?
I-Indeed.
As it happens, Sensei,
I have a favor to a—
Another serving.
As many as you'd like.
With Sensei on our side, we can rest assured.
Today is the last day for Psiren.
Well, I'll give it a shot.
Still, though,
that's an awful lot of people.
Yeah. I don't know
what Psiren is thinking,
sending prior notice to newspapers
throughout the country of upcoming thefts.
Newspaper reporters, spectators,
and even Psiren groupies show up as a result.
She's quite popular, huh?
Well, that popularity ends tonight.
We'll leave it in your hands, Sensei.
Now then, I'm going to go
check on the security situation.
You know, Brother,
I'm surprised you took on this job.
I've taken an interest...
in this alchemist thief.
Oh, no!
Hold it!
What?
There are many ways
to use alchemy.
But I won't allow you
to use it for stealing!
Besides, thanks to you,
I also got treated like a thief!
Now apologize,
for all you're worth!
I've caught you!
Y-You're a woman?!
It's a shame I can't
show you my face.
I'm terribly good-looking.
Dammit, what are you doing?!
Children ought to be in
bed by now, pipsqueak.
Who are you calling an ultra-hyper-pipsqueak?!
Al... Al!
Where the hell did he go, for crying out loud?
You...
This is a surprise. Who would've thought that the kindly nurse
is actually the Phantom Thief Psiren?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I just came here to
get some medicine.
Yeah, medicine that you
transmuted through alchemy.
You lying bitch!
I don't see how I'm a liar.
I am an incredible beauty, right?
Just like I told you.
That's not the issue here!
Brother!
Brother, bad news...
Is something the matter?
What do you think is the matter?!
She's Psiren! Look!
The transmutation circle on her chest is more proof than anything!
A lot can happen in one's life.
You kids probably
wouldn't understand.
What?!
I understand.
I heard earlier that the hospital is going to be demolished.
Clara-san, you had no choice but to become a thief in order to save the hospital, right?
That's it, right, Clara-san?
Th-That's right.
I didn't want to become a thief.
But in order to save
the patients here,
I had no choice.
I knew it.
You're such a kind person.
Sensei!
Sensei! There's another notice from Psiren...
Is something the matter?
Sensei?
It looks like there's less security around this time.
Yeah. The owner of this mansion is a very cautious man, you see.
There's a little trap
set up inside the mansion.
A trap?
Just watch, and you'll understand.
This time, Psiren has had it for sure!
But the unexpected could always happen. If it does, we'll be counting on you.
What should we do, Brother?
Oh, no!
A trap?
Kid...
Why did you help me out?
I didn't particularly help you out.
There are times when
wrongdoing may be necessary.
That's all I thought.
If that's what it takes
to save the hospital...
What's so funny?!
It's just that you sound like such a grown-up.
I am a grown-up!
Right. As a grown woman,
I have to repay my debt to you.
Is there anything you'd like me to do for you?
Just answer me one thing.
If you're an alchemist, you must've
heard about the Philosopher's Stone.
If you have any information about it, tell me.
I have to get that stone,
no matter what.
Sorry.
It doesn't look like I can help you.
How about instead,
if you ever find out where the stone is, you let me know? I'll steal it for you.
Hey!
I'm glad you're able
to save the hospital.
Sure! Thanks to you!
What's going on here?
Don't tell me she tricked us...
No way! Clara-san would be
the last person to do something like that.
There has to be
some kind of mistake!
The only mistakes going on are inside that head of yours!
Clara has robbed
your head of clarity!
That's terrible, Brother,
saying it like that!
You mustn't argue.
It goes against the will of God.
Clara-san...
You...?
It's too bad about the hospital.
I tried to save it,
but I was too late.
I was so beside myself
with grief that I...
became a nun!
Clara-san!
I'll just bet.
It's true!
Those who believe will be saved.
And there are still others
whom I can save.
For example, this convent.
It will soon be demolished!
I-I knew it!
You're right! This time,
you've got to stick with it, please!
We'll give you our support, too!
Brother! Bad news!
What is it?!
They're saying that Psiren appeared again!
The whole city is in an uproar!
She's done it!
Now the convent can be saved!
There's some kind of mistake.
Right, Brother?
What are you, an idiot?! Quit being such a nice guy already! She's a con artist!
She's just been teasing us
and having herself a laugh!
Don't say it like that, Brother!
You shouldn't fight.
Stop it, boys.
Why, you! What are you this time, in that getup?
I know! You've become a schoolteacher, right?
You're fighting for a school
that's soon to be destroyed!
That's it, right?
Isn't that right, Clara-san?!
Y-Yes, yes. Well done.
Stop jerking us around!
What are you?
Are you just a thief after all?
A common criminal, who uses alchemy for her own selfish interests?!
Well, that's a good question.
You're a grown-up, right?
Think about it for yourself.
Extra! Extra!
Another notice from Psiren!
What are you so pleased about?
Psiren is just a common criminal, right?
What are you talking about? We owe Psiren for saving the city of Aquroya.
She's our star of hope, you know!
Your star of hope?
This city—the City of Water, Aquroya—
sinks a little bit into
the water every year.
In another five years, the whole city will be wiped out at the bottom of the lake.
Because of that,
everyone else fled the city.
That made us all so lonesome. At least until Psiren appeared.
But thanks to Psiren,
life has returned to the city.
Reporters from all over the country
and tourists alike
come here in the hope of
catching a glimpse of Psiren.
Before disappearing under the water,
she has made Aquroya bloom one last time.
What does it mean, Brother?
Could it be that Clara-san
became a thief to save the city?
Maybe. The one thing
I can say for sure...
is that she tricked me—
the Fullmetal Alchemist.
She's going to pay for that offense, at least.
I thought you would come,
kid.
Pretty fantastic, isn't it?
A date here, on the water.
Shut up, you crook.
Dear me, the same could be said of you, couldn't it?
You want the Philosopher's Stone, right?
The desire to have an object...
is the same in both of us.
Maybe so.
However...
there is something that's different.
What we use our alchemy for,
and the burdens we each bear.
Here I go, kid.
I did it...
That was pretty sharp, kid.
I'm sure you'll turn into a fine man.
Once you do, let's fight again.
Next time, as a man and a woman.
Clara-san...
Let me tell you one last thing.
It's about the Philosopher's Stone.
What?
Go to the city of Xenotime and have a look.
I've heard that there's somebody there researching the Philosopher's Stone.
Xenotime...
What, are you still angry?
I had no choice, you know.
She was, after all,
a common criminal.
She was not!
She wasn't just
a common criminal.
Brother, you said yourself that sometimes, wrongdoing is necessary, didn't you?
Clara-san was...
Clara-san was a kind person.
You really think so too, Brother!
About that...
I'm not sure.
Say, it's a little bit warm in here.
Could I get you to lower the zipper on my chest?
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 11: "Land of Stones, Part 1"
Another me...
Another Brother...
And a red stone that binds the four of us together.